James "Jim" Bishop Phone: 0421 219 018

Email: jimbishop@iinet.net.au

#### **OVERVIEW**

System Administrator with over ten years of on job experience, Analytical thinker with a knack for working out complex problems. Have worked supporting a large number of high performance GNU/Linux workstations and servers in a film studio environment, Building HPC hardware and coming up with budget constrained solutions as a solo Sysadmin for an architecture/previz firm. Have been working in the technology field in one way or another since my high school days.

## **SKILLS**

VMWare Workstation/Player/ESX Kickstart

Shell scripting, BASH, CSH, KSH Microsoft Exchange

Yum Package Manager Juniper Pulse VPN and Softether VPN

RHEL, CentOS, Solaris, OBSD, FBSD OpenBSD Packet Filter

Active Directory Legacy System Support

Sophos AV Admin and Deployment Package Creation and Deployment

Hardware Specialist BIND, DHCPD, NIS / YP

Flix Specialist OSX, OSX Server, Deploystudio

FlexLM, ADLM License Daemons Keen Documenter

Cfengine Configuration Level Headed

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Support Engineer, Animal Logic - Oct 2008 to Apr 2016 (7 Years, 7 Months)**

Worked at Animal as a Support Engineer / System Administrator, <u>Responsibilities included</u> supporting a company of from 200 to 500 people pending on the productions that we had running as Animal Logic was a film company. The job was extremely varied in what I was doing and covered almost all aspects of System Administration and Support. I directly took care of Linux support for the team, VM support, Sophos Anti-Virus administration, Hardware trial and implementation, Foundry Flix support and beta development. I specialised mainly in Linux which we ran company wide on near all workstations and servers.

Some day to day activities included License server trouble shooting, 3D software trouble shooting, Exchange and AD administration, creation deletion and suspension of user accounts, Resource management and prioritisation with co operation of senior administrators and render wranglers, Documentation of processes, working on new processes, Optimising and automation of old processes to make the job more efficient and quick, and also hands on interaction with the artists, staff and clients as this job was rather end to end.

<u>Achievments included</u> working at Animal Logic for seven and a half years, starting in late 2008, Contributing to many releases that the company worked on including The Lego Movie, The Great Gatsby, X-Men: Days of Future Past and Avengers: Age of

Ultron to name a couple. (All of these can be verified at my imdb page: <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm4965095/">http://www.imdb.com/name/nm4965095/</a>). I was sent to LA to set up and optimise our field office over there. I successfully trained many new technical operation staff in their jobs. I implemented and tested the client side VMWare solution that many of our workstations used to best utilise the resources we had. Quite a few of my scripts and tools made it into our OS builds and were used by artists and staff daily. I also had a part in the development of Foundry Flix which a team mate in the US and myself gave valuable input into the creation and testing of this software. I also supported a successful training program which brang many young artists into the film / 3D industry.

# Systems Manager, Enspire Digital - Jan 2008 to Oct 2008 (10 Months)

Worked here as the Systems Manager and Technician, <u>Responsibilities included</u> Support via E-mail and phone also On-site support taking care of customers servers, workstations, networks and laptops. Managing other technicians. Building high performance servers, workstations and media-centres. Performing QA on built machines. Building and tuning special order overclocked watercooled workstations and gaming rigs. Troubleshooting complex hardware problems. Assuring deadlines were met. Helping users and businesses decide which systems to buy to fit their needs.

<u>Achievments included</u> having one of my machines featured on the cover of Atomic MPC Magazine, Writing tools which automated the new machine build process and standardising the new machine builds software, hardware and firmware settings wise.

# System Adminstrator, Ivolve Studios - Jan 2006 to Jan 2007 (1 Year, 1Month)

This company is an architecture and previz (Pre Visualisation in 3D) firm, my role was that of the sole System Adminstrator for the company. Responsibilities included Supporting artists on a day to day basis. Designing and building the network and render farm (HPC cluster for rendering high resolution 3D stills and video). Optimisation of the workstation build. Maintaining the filer, firewall, and system servers (AD, DHCP, DNS etc). Maintaining the switches and performing backups.

<u>Achievments included</u> building and optimising of the company render farm, implementing a backup solution where none existed, the automation of many processes through scripts and the implementation of monitoring systems with graphs on important data points (Network throughput, Quotas, Utilisation, etc)

### Freelance

In my spare time I take care of several clients business, office and home computing needs. I have been doing this continuously since my teenage years.

## **EDUCATION**

HP Linux Certification
HP Linux System Administration Certification
Cert 2 IT, Tafe
TESOL Certification
Higher School Certificate

References are available on request.